blackdiamondbuilder.com 2011-05-16

# Privacy Policy | Black Diamond Builder

Your privacy is very important to us, and we will treat your data with care and respect. We know that you care how information and data about you is collected, used and shared. This Privacy Statement describes our privacy policy and details how we collect, use, and/or disseminate the information you provide. We reserve the right to change this Statement at any time and urge you to review our Statement regularly to familiarize yourself with any changes.

_**By visiting our website, using our online products/services, and/or by voluntarily submitting information to us via online forms, advertisement responses, and/or electronic mail, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Statement.**_

**Who We Are**

Ultimate Builder MV, LLC has developed and licenses a system software product called Black Diamond Builder which allows Network Marketers to promote a legal and ethical network marketing opportunity and/or Client program and/or opportunities or programs of their choice. The Black Diamond Builder system is designed to be used exclusively to promote the products and Services offered by the system. However, due to the fact that each Black Diamond Builder account is controlled by an independent representative, we cannot guarantee how the system and privacy information will be managed by these representatives.

Ultimate Builder, MV LLC operates and manages the Black Diamond Builder System to assist network marketers in the building of their business on the Web. Individuals that subscribe to the Black Diamond Builder System do so in one of two forms: prospects (sometimes referred to as contacts), and Members. Individual subscriptions to the Black Diamond Builder System are referred to as a "Member" in the Black Diamond Builder System.

To cater to both you (the Customer) and our Members, we may be required to collect, use, and share certain information. The type of information we collect, together with a description of how we use and/or share it, is described below.

**Information Collection and Use**

Ultimate Builder MV, LLC (dba – Black Diamond Builder) our partners, and the independent representative who are Members are the owners of the information collected on BlackDiamondBuilder.com.

**Registration**

In order to use this Web site, a user MAY first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide unique identifiers (such as, username and password), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site. If a person or company chooses to enroll in our network marketing business opportunity, we are sometimes required to collect the persons/user’s social security number and if a company, we are sometimes required to collect their EIN number. When we request these numbers, it is because they are used to comply with IRS requirements and to provide this information to our associated network marketing business.

**Order**

We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s orders. In addition, the contact information is given to the network marketing company for the purpose of enrollment. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user.

**Information Use**

We will use personal information that we gather about you to provide the services that you have requested. In addition, if you have a free trial account with Black Diamond Builder, then we will use the information gathered about you to share more information about our business in an attempt to convince you to make a purchase from us or our associated companies. Black Diamond Builder and the person/affiliate who sent you to this site will be granted access to your personal contact (name, phone number, and email) information so that they can communicate with you in an attempt to “sell” various products, services, and memberships to you.

**Profile**

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do share your profile with other third parties unless specifically explained in this Privacy Policy. In such cases, your profile is shared together with your personally identifiable information.

YOUR PAYMENT INFORMATION IS NEVER SHARED FOR ANY REASON WITH ANY OUTSIDE THIRD PARTY UNLESS REQUIRED BY LAW, EXCEPT FOR THE PURPOSE OF ENROLLMENT IN OUR MLM OPPORTUNITIES.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by you.

By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. See the “Profile” section. 

**Log Files**

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are in some cases linked to personally identifiable information.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons, Web Bugs, CSS, and similar functionality)**

We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are tied to users’ personally identifiable information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section.

**Communications from the Site**

**Special Offers and Updates**

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

**Service Announcements**

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

**Customer Service**

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.

**Sharing**

**Legal Disclaimer**

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site. 

**Third Parties**

We use the information you have voluntarily provided to cause information, offers, products, and/or services that appear to us to be consistent with your expressed interests to be directed to you. This is typically accomplished by using your information to direct to you information, offers, products, and/or services from us and/or one of our affiliated companies. Your information may, therefore, ultimately be used for marketing purposes by us, our affiliated companies, and/or any one or more the associated businesses with which we work.

We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Statement. For example, we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate.

After we share your information with our affiliated companies and/or any of the several businesses with which we work, we lose control over how they will use, collect, and/or disseminate your information. Accordingly, we recommend that you review the Privacy Statements of the corresponding affiliated companies with whom we have shared your information in order to acquaint yourself with their information collection, use, and/or sharing policies.

You understand and agree that Black Diamond Builder is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites, and you agree that Black Diamond Builder is not responsible for how such information is ultimately used.

These are the instances in which we will share users’ personal information:

We Share Personal Contact Information with third parties. If you want to ensure that your information is never shared with any third party, you must request to be unsubscribed or cancelled from our service. Failure to unsubscribe or cancel your service will imply that you are interested in having your personal information shared with various third parties.

**Third Party Intermediaries**

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**Service Providers**

We partner with other third parties to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services and for purposes referenced in their privacy policies.

**Approved Lead Vendors**

We allow carefully-screened Approved Lead Vendors to be listed in our back office. Under certain circumstances, we may share your contact information with one or more of these Approved Lead Vendors. They may use this information to contact you via telephone, email or direct mail to inform you about an upcoming lead special, conference call or other promotional opportunity which could potentially benefit you.

**Business Transitions**

In the event Black Diamond Builder goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users’ personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

**Choice/Opt-out**

Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site only by completely opting-out of our service and/or canceling a paid subscription to our service.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the unsubscribe instructions sent with every email.

**Links**

This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Black Diamond Builder, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Tell-A-Friend or Warm Market Wizard**

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. Black Diamond Builder will automatically send the friend a one-time opt-in email inviting them to opt-in to receiving emails from Black Diamond Builder. Black Diamond Builder stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. The friend may request the removal of this information from our database by following the unsubscribe instructions sent with every email.

**Children’s privacy**

Protecting the privacy of the young is important to us. Therefore, you cannot use this site if you are not 18 years old. If you are not 18 years old you are not permitted to access this website for any reason. Because of this, we never knowingly collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 18, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under the age of 18.

**Security**

This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry – SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment.

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to support@BlackDiamondBuilder.com.

**Supplementation of Information**

In order for this Web site to properly fulfill its obligation to users it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources. 

**Enhancement of Marketing Profile**

We purchase third party marketing data and add it to our existing user database to better target our advertising and provide pertinent offers we think our users would be interested in. We use this information to enhance or overlay the ‘profile’ of individual users. This aggregate marketing data is therefore tied to the users’ personally identifiable information. See also the “Profile.”

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done in the member back office or by emailing our Customer Support at support@BlackDiamondBuilder.com.

**Notification of Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement in places that we deem appropriate. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

**Contact Information**

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: support@BlackDiamondBuilder.com

www.BlackDiamondBuilder.com

**ACKNOWLEDGMENT**

BY CLICKING THE PROVIDED CHECK BOX, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ THIS AGREEMENT AND AGREE TO ALL ITS TERMS AND CONDITIONS. YOU HAVE INDEPENDENTLY EVALUATED THE DESIRABILITY OF PARTICIPATING IN THE BLACK DIAMOND BUILDER SERVICE AND ARE NOT RELYING ON ANY REPRESENTATION, GUARANTEE, OR STATEMENT OTHER THAN AS SET FORTH IN THIS AGREEMENT.
